Guide to the Urie Bronfenbrenner papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
Bronfenbrenner, Urie papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Urie Bronfenbrenner papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
23-13-954
Urie, Bronfenbrenner 1917-
28.9 cubic feet.
Correspondence, news clippings, reviews, professional writings, lectures, vita, bibliographies, and other papers relating to the career of Urie Bronfenbrenner, including educational videocassettes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, news clippings, reviews, professional writings, lectures, material from the White House Conference on Children, vita, bibliographies, subject files, and other papers relating to the career of Urie Bronfenbrenner, including educational videocassettes.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Human Development and Family Studies, Cornell University.
Urie Bronfenbrenner was born in Moscow, Russia on April 29, 1917 and moved to the United States six years later. He attended Cornell University where he double majored in psychology and music in 1938. He received his M.A. at Harvard and his Ph.D. from the University of Michigan in 1942. That same year he was inducted into the Army where he served as a psychologist in the Air Corps and the Office of Strategic Services and then served in the Army Medical Corps. In 1948 he accepted a position in the Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies at Cornell. He did extensive research and writings in the field of human development, international comparisons of child rearing, and his development of the theories of Human Ecology and the Bio-ecological Model. He was one of the founding members of Head Start. He received six honorary degrees, and was awarded numerous awards, including in 1996 the first American Psychological Association Award for Lifetime Contribution to Developmental Psychology in the service of Science and Society.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, news clippings, reviews, professional writings, lectures, material from the White House Conference on Children, vita, bibliographies, subject files, and other papers relating to the career of Urie Bronfenbrenner, including educational videocassettes.
Also, a tape recording of a discussion about child development between Urie Bronfenbrenner and citizens of Clifton Springs, New York, in June, 1970, and a phonodisc "The Impact of Peers."
Includes an interview with Bronfenbrenner, Joy D. Osofsky and John Condry.
Subject files relating to daycare issues, mother/father/infant relationships, adoption, and family issues, with reference to these subjects in Japan, the U.S.S.R., Norway, China, Hungary, Germany, Turkey, Israel, etc.
Includes awards and films "Three Worlds of Childhood" and "Center for Improvement of Undergraduate Education: HDFS 115 Study".
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bronfenbrenner, Urie,1917-; Bronfenbrenner, Urie,1917-; Condry, John C.; Osofsky, Joy D.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Human Development and Family Studies.; White House Conference on Children and Youth
Subjects:
Child development--Japan.; Child development--Russia.; Child development--Norway.; Child development--China.; Child development--Hungary.; Child development--Germany.; Child development--Turkey.; Family--Study and teaching.; Child development--Israel.; School-age child care--Study and teaching; Adoption--Study and teaching.; Head Start programs--United States.
Places:
Clifton Springs (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes .; Sound recordings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
The videotaped lecture given by Professor Bronfenbrenner, The American Family, Who Cares? from the Media Services records, #21-36-2566 has been digitized and can be found on Cornell's Library Media Space website along with other related films.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Subject Files, Lecture Notes, Trip Files
Boxes 1-8, 13, 26, 27, 30
Series II. Grant Files
Boxes 13
Series III. Published Works
Boxes 9-12, 16-18, 25
Series IV. Correspondence Files
Boxes 18-20, 26, 30
Series V. Researcher Files
Boxes 20-23, 27
Series VI. Audiotapes and Sound Recordings
Boxes 23-24
Series VII. Videotapes and Films
Boxes 24, 32
Series VIII. Interviews
Boxes 25-26
Series IX. Programs of Interest and/or Involvement for Bronfenbrenner
Box 26
Series X. Statistics Figures (Paper and Transperency Copies)
Boxes 26
Series XI. Articles in which Bronfenbrenner is Cited or Quoted
Boxes 26-27
Series XII. Awards
Boxes 14-15,30, Mapcase Folder 1
Series XIII. Biographical
Boxes 1,3,26,30
Series XIV. Photographs
Boxes 1,30
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Subject Files, Lecture Notes, Trip Files
  - Transcript: Bronfenbrenner, Joy Osofsky and John Condry discussion, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters: Congress, Senate, 1961-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mondale, Walter, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mondale, Califano, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Negatives (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Massachusetts Governor's Commission for Family and Children, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - University of Michigan, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charlotte Observer, North Carolina, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The State, Columbia, North Carolina, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Child Rearing in Changing Families - What Can Families Do? (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ithaca Journal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Response to Washington Post Article, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Talks - ISSBD, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Social class through time, space and science, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Grant foundation talk (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cornell Chronicle, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Washington, 1987-03-30-1987-03-31 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - USSR: Pictures (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Soviet Field Notes - Rough notes and final draft, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Charlotte Development - USA-USSR, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - USSR - Preliminary report, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Institutional Approaches to Cultural Deprivation - USA-USSR, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Informing on Associates, ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Makarenko and the Collective Family, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Upbringing in Collective Settings in Switzerland and USSR (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Soviet Day School vs. Boarding, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Report: Making of the New Soviet Man, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - A New Approach to Communicating with the Russians, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Informing Associates Among Soviet and American School Children: An Experimental Study (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - How Russians Build Character, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Introduction to Soviet Family, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Changing Soviet Family (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Psychological Bases of Soviet Secrecy (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Some Possible Effects of a Large-Scale American Shelter Program on the Soviet Union and Other Nations (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Problems in Communicating with Americans about the Soviet Union (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Soviet Methods of Upbringing and Their Effects, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Kegan, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - America's Most Dangerous Prejudice, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Lecture in USSR (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 115 Lectures, 1971;1974 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 115 - Scientific Method I-III (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Social Class Differences, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Lecture #24, 1963-11-24 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Psychology 41 Unit VIII (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Family Relations (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Sex Differences (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Heterosexual Relationships (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Lecture #2, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Parental Role Differences (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Family Authority Structure, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Lecture #28, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Lecture #22, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 115 - Analyzing Hypotheses (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Committee Hearing, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Misrepresentative Statement on Hearing in Congressional Record, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Children and Youth of the Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, 1971, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Lecture #26, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Legislation, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 61-64)
  - Hearings Before the Committee on Ways and Means, 91st Congress, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Child Development National Advisory Committee (HEW), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Legislation, Current: Conable, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - White House Conference Address, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Child Development Legislation, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 69-70)
  - Child Development Act, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - U.S. Office of Education Task Force, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - White House Conference on Families, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - National Home Start Evaluation: Final Report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Head Start - Notes and Lectures (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Head Start - Advisory Panel, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Head Start - OSPRI, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Head Start Correspondence, 1967-1994 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Head Start Newsletter, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Head Start Reminiscences (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Head Start in the 1980's (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Head Start Articles (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - "Head Start Act Amendments " Draft to Hon. Thomas S. Foley, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Beyond the Murphy Brown Debate - Ideas for Family Policy, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Amended - Head Start Act (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - History of East Henderson - Head Start Center - "Child Development", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Ethics Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Commissioner's Advisory Panel, ca. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Advisory Committee on Head Start - Report on Subcommittee Research (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Moscow APN Exchange - 1st round, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues (SPSSI), 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - South Carolina, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Outstanding Achievement - Michigan, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Charlotte, North Carolina, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 94-95)
  - National Council for Families and Television, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - United Way Kick-off, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Kyoto Dinner - Japanese (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Universitat Bielefeld, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Fachbereich 8 Psychologie und Fachbereich 9 Erziehung Seissenschaft... (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Report on the External Review Committee for the Program in Social Ecology, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Annual Conference of the Department of Public Information for Non-governmental Organizations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Syracuse - Development of Child (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Social Psychology - A Misnomer (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - "Whence and Whither" (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Experimental Human Ecology, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Kolloquium, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Reprints, 1962;1966 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Notes on Russian Trip, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Leipzig, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lecture - HDFS, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lecture - 115 HD and FS F-4242 Human Behavior, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lecture 115 F-4431 summary of Methodology, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Questions to Learn From, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Analyzing Discussion (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Research Design, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Methods of Control (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hypothesis (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Logic of Testing Hypothesis (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Society for the Investigation of Human Ecology, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Notification and Statement of Grant Award, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Urie: Russell Sage, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Studies of Human Development-in-Context, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Family in a Changing Context, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Use of Tests with Disadvantaged, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Parent Behavior Questionnaire - old stuff when study was active (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Family Life Study (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Parent Behavior Instruments Past and Present (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - HDFS 685 Section I - Fall, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Open School: A View from the World (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - HDFS 115 Research Report: An Experiment in College Training (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Head Start Report (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - HE Washington, D.C., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Family Size, 1959-1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Marital Status and Living Arrangements, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Family Mobility (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Family Components by Race (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Asch Experiment Response, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Visit to Boston, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Yale Advisory Committee on Infant Care Leave, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Division 8 Newsletter, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Children and Foundations - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Developmental Research and Public Policy (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Impact of Family Assistant Act, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Task Force Drafts, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - White House Conference on Children, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Day Care in Context, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Evaluating Head Start, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - White House Conference on Families, 1969, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Frankfort, 1968, 1967, 1976, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Prejudice Study, ca. 1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Intervention Paper, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - WBZ Program, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "An Older Child Shall Lead Them" (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Israeli Address - On Making Human Beings Human (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Association for the Aid of Crippled Children, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - [?] Panel (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Some Psychological Aspect of Negotiation with the Soviets, ca. 1958 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Adults and Peers as Sources of Conformity and Autonomy, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Statement of the Committee on Labor and Public Welfare of the U. S. Senate, 1964;1966 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Psychology as Core Discipline in Home Economics (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - A Social Psychologist Looks at the Soviet Union, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Commencement at Cornell (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Soviet Notes (to Don), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - How Do We Change?, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Black Students in Cornell Classrooms, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - [Introduction], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Presentations in German, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Contemporary Trends in Soviet Society (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Soviet Letters and Impressions, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Soviet Views of America at War, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Stichting congres ipa, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - USSR Seminar, 1976, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Bill and Veto, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Testimony before Senate Sub-Committee, 1971;1973 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Who Cares for America's Children?, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Human Development and Public Policy, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - McGill Trip - Psychological Science in Developmental Perspective, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Conference Proceedings -University of Southampton, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - ASFS, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - American Psychological Society, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Waterloo, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Zero to Three, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Carter Family Policy, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Beyond the Mother-Infant Dyad - Continuity or Change?, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Senate Sub-Committee/Children and Youth, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - National Policy - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Congressional Seminar (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Lecture (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - "The Next Generation of Americans: In International Perspective" (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - School of Effectiveness, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Two Worlds - Reviews, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Nature-Nurture Reconceptualized, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - München, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Zürich, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - American Enterprise Institute on Head Start Policy, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - IYF - January, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The World from Two Perspectives, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Development of Human Behavior - Introductory Lecture (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Men, Moonships and Morality, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - American Research on Development in Context, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Set as Mom and Dad (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Public Policy, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Brigham Young, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Family Matters: Common Concern of Business and Parents, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Sage Convocation - December 4, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Child and Family Service Act: Testimony, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Social and Behavioral Development - Prepared for the President's Biomedical Research Panel, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - On Making Human Beings Human, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - I.Q. Lecture (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Socialization and Social Class, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - March - University of Alabama, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Trip Journal, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Family at Christmastime, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Testimony before AIA Panel, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - American[?] Historical Society, ca. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Children and Youth at Risk (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Symposium - John Clausen, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - American Psychological Society Meeting - Award, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - DeWitt Commencement, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Behavioral Science Research, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Society for Research in Child Development Meeting, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Growing up Male in the 1980's, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Revolutionary Perspective on Child Abuse and Neglect, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Caring Corporation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - School of Management, 1984-06-28 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Human Development, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Symposium in Honor of Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Thematic Sessions on Cross-National Research in Sociology, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Society for Research in Child Development (SRCD) Symposium on Organism-Environment Interaction, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - History, Science and Technology, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Symposium, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Spiritual Literacy (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Research and Public Policy, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Kobe, Japan, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Science, Children, and Families - What We Don't Want to Know, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Children and Families: The Silent Revolution, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Little Black Sambo, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - The Friend of the Sick and Poor, ca. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - The Tower Club Symposium, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Family Impact Seminar, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - NAS Advisory Committee on Child Development, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
  - Ecology of Human Development (EHD) Conference Address (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - SRCD [?] Talk (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Dornbush - Evaluation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Evaluation of Bronfenbrenner's Questionnaire for Children Concerning Parental Behavior, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - A Glossary of Common Statistical Terms (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - APA, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - President's Biomedical Research Panel, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Report of the President's Biomedical Research Panel, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Society for Research in Child Development, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - National Council for Children and TV, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Principal, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Random House - editor, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Childhood Series, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 71-72)
  - Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The American Family, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Developmental Transitions, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Analysis of Dyad, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Microsystem - manuscript notes, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Interactive Systems, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Academy of Educational Development, Advisory Board, Family Institute, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bronfenbrenner: Retirement Letters, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "The American Family: Who Cares?", 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Children and Families, ca. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Three Worlds of Childhood, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bronfenbrenner and Weiss (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bronfenbrenner, "Freedom and Discipline Across the Decades" (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 3 - Before We Are Born, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Nature with Nurture, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - From Cry to Conversation (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Interplay of Organism and Environment in Early Development - The Case of Low Birth Weight (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Born Too Early or Too Late (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Male Vulnerability (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Chapter 2: The Changing Family in a Changing World (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - The Developmental Effects of Low Birth Weight (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Comparative Ecology of Human Development (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Social Ecology of Human Development (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - On the Making of New Men (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Childhood - Program I, Episode 1 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Childhood - Program I, Episode 1a (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Childhood - Program I, Episode 2 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Childhood: Points to be Made, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Childhood: Treatments - Current (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Brademas Bill NR 15882 (services to children and their families), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - The Child and Family Services Act, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Synanon Foundation, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Research for Better Schools (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Ecology of Human Development in Retrospect and Prospect (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - The Context of Development and the Development of Context (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Day Care in the First Year - Ricciuti (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Daycare and Attachment - Cochran (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Daycare Review - ER (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Daycare (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Daycare Symposium - APA (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Effects - Bowlby, Ainsworth (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Isolation - Dennis (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - House is Institution - Rheingold (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Institutional Effects - Spits, Hospitalization (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Institutional Effects (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Family vs. Kibbutz (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Gerwitz (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hospitals - Douglas & Rutter (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Religious Differences (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Exploratory Behavior & Curiosity (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Studies of Twins reared apart: Primary (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Twins reared apart (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Twins reared apart: Shields (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Twins apart: Burt (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Twins: Statistics (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Cowan, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Adoption studies: Intelligence (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Adoption Leahy (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Adoption: Scarr & McAvay (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Adoption (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Skeels Experiment (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Skeels Background (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - The Impact of Environment (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Adoption: Burks (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Talking with America - Urie's Workshop (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - HDFS 610, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Spring
  - HDFS 488 Lecture Notes (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - CD 115 Lecture notes, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 115 Scientific Method I-III (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 115 Last Lectures (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 115 Lecture Notes (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - A Social Psychologist's Look at the Soviet Union (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Allowing for Soviet Motives and Perceptions (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - In the Shadow of August (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Contribution of Psychology to International Relations (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Mirror Image (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - China (Box 5, Folder 42)